# Yusuf Muhammad

At a very young age as a student in high school, Curious to know how to program I developed a serious interest in programming. This keen interest in computers along with passion for solving problems prompted me to choose Computer Science as my major. This decision gave me ample opportunity to consolidate my creative energies and harness my technical aptitude. I have built so many products in Software Engineering.

As a passionate Software Engineer with experience in Software Engineering, I enjoy implementing light and scalable solutions using the best Agile practices for the satisfaction I get by overcoming challenges. I am very flexible with different technologies, so I can learn and adapt to new environments quickly and build solutions around them.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# Decagon, Edo Tech Park / Software Engineer

DECEMBER 2021 - PRESENT, Benin City Edo - Nigeria

- Built projects with NodeJS, React, and Javascript.
- Created a basic Node application that performs CRUD operation (Create, Read, Update and Delete) with MongoDB
- Built APIs (Endpoints) with Express and Containerized the application with Docker.
- Built Diverse Application with MERN Stack including a Banking Application, Performance tracker (Score card) E-Commerce Application.
- Writing unit and integration test.

## T.M.B Express Ltd / Head of I.C.T

NOVEMBER 2020 - DECEMBER 2021, Gusau, Zamfara - Nigeria

- Built an online web portal to ease digital logistic services,
- Worked closely with the administrative & technical team in the resolution of potentially complex technical issues, & communicated the relevant corrective actions.
- Contributed to the growth of the company by assisting in bringing in new innovative features (USSD based application that acts as a mobile marketing platform for logistic services).
- Collaborating with the rest of the engineering team to design and launch new features.
- Writing unit and integration test

# AKBAR Reliance Enterprises – Network Engineer - JULY 2019 - NOVEMBER 2020, Katsina - Nigeria Responsibilities as an Asst. Manager:

 Overseeing daily business operations, Developing and implementing growth strategies, Training students and staff, Hiring employees and Analyzing accounting and financial data

## As a Network Engineer:

- Installing and configuring computer networks and systems, identifying and solving any problems that arise with computer networks and systems.
- monitoring computer networks and systems to identify how performance can be improved and providing network administration and support.

Fara Park 2 Estate, Sangotedo, Lagos Nigeria. +2347068284460

Email: <a href="mailto:yusufanka54@gmail.com">yusufanka54@gmail.com</a>
Github:<a href="mailto:https://github.com/yusufA">https://github.com/yusufA</a>

nka Linkedin:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/yusu fanka/

#### **TECHNOLOGIES**

- Typescript
- Javascript
- Angular
- React
- MongoDB
- GraphQL
- Nodejs
- Express Framework
- HTML 5
- CSS 3
- Tailwind
- Postgresql
- Heroku
- Jira
- CI /CD Pipelines
- Version Control with Git and Github.
- Test-Driven Development.

### **PERSONAL SKILLS**

- Pair Programming
- Agile and Leadership Skill
- Strong team work ethics
- Creative and Problem solving.
- I.T Essentials
- Networking

#### **PROJECTS**

# ScoreCard(in progress) - Decagon / Team of 6

- Scorecard is a web application that allows Decadevs extracts the weekly performance records from the performance tracker and stores this record for future reference purposes.
- The Decadev logs into the application and views the weekly performance result for that week while also has the option to compare the recent performance records against past performance records.
- The Decadev can also take the skill test to get evaluation on their skill level
- Technologies Typescript, Express, MongoDB and React
- Links:

BackEnd-https://github.com/decadevs/live-project-score-card-sq011a-group-2-node group 2 live project.git

FrontEnd-https://github.com/decadevs/live-project-score-card-sq011a-group-2-frontend-group-2-project-node-sq011

# **Accessified - Decagon**

- Accessified is a platform for assessing and evaluating real-world and real-time coding skills. Accessified aims to screen, train, certify and hire talents faster.
- ❖ Technologies Typescript, Nodejs, Express, MongoDB
- Link- <a href="https://github.com/yusufAnka/Accessified.git">https://github.com/yusufAnka/Accessified.git</a>

### E-Commerce Application (T.M.B online catalog)

- Designed Shopping Cart Using HTML and CSS
- Implemented React Components For Product List, Filter, Cart.
- Technologies Used Node.js, Express and MongoDB for the backend. And React for frontend.
- ❖ Link- https://github.com/yusufAnka/T.M.B---catalog.git

#### **EDUCATION**

# Aisha Kwaku And Associates CISCO Academy Kano / CCNA, Python,

I.T Essentials and Cyber security courses.

SEPTEMBER 2019 - FEBRUARY 2020, Kano - Nigeria.

#### Federal University Birnin Kebbi — B.Sc. Computer Science

OCTOBER 2014 - NOVEMBER 2018, Birnin Kebbi - Nigeria.

CGPA 4.23/5.00

- Nigerian Association of Computer Science Students' (FUBK Chapter) Service Award
- Students' Representative Council (FUBK) Service Award.

# Waziri Umaru Federal Polytechnic Birnin Kebbi/N.D

MARCH 2012 - SEPTEMBER 2014, Birnin Kebbi - Nigeria.

#### **CERTIFICATIONS**

Accelerated Jobberman Soft Skills Training - June, 2022
 Scrum Fundamentals Certified - April, 2022

• EF Standard English Test (EF SET) - April, 2022

CCNA Routing and Switching
 Cisco IT Essentials
 February, 2020
 October, 2019

Cisco IT Essentials
 Cisco Introduction to Cybersecurity
 Sept, 2019.

#### LANGUAGES:

- English
- Hausa
- Arabic (Intermediate)